cmog.org 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Corning Museum of Glass

The Corning Museum of Glass (“CMoG”) knows that your privacy is important to you, and we want you to know that it is important to us too. We created this Privacy Policy to explain the types of information we collect through our websites at cmog.org and the various social networking platforms that we use (collectively, the “Site”), how we will use, share and protect this information once it is collected, and how you can opt out of some of our uses of your information.

The Site is owned and operated by The Corning Museum of Glass, a not-for-profit museum (referred to collectively in this policy as “we,” “us,” “our” and other similar pronouns).

## Email Communication - Your Choices

You can opt out of our communications to you by using the opt out link in the communication you receive or use any of the links below:

General CMoG mailing list: [Unsubscribe](https://cmog.us7.list-manage.com/unsubscribe?u=37e97ca4783d75c4c341cf1f1&id=0454fc673b)  
Shops mailing list: [Unsubscribe](https://cmog.us7.list-manage.com/unsubscribe?u=37e97ca4783d75c4c341cf1f1&id=68a399c5cd)  
Steuben mailing list: [Unsubscribe](https://steuben.us7.list-manage.com/unsubscribe?u=37e97ca4783d75c4c341cf1f1&id=57b54d0b66)  
New Glass Review mailing list: [Unsubscribe](https://cmog.us7.list-manage.com/unsubscribe?u=37e97ca4783d75c4c341cf1f1&id=e8da40bc75)

You may also request opt out by emailing [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d2bfb3bbbebbbcb5bebba1a6a192b1bfbdb5fcbda0b5)

We may still contact you in connection with your transactions with us, and to respond to you if you contact us.

## Website Data - What information is collected on this Site?

“Personal Information” is information that can be used to identify you as an individual person or allow someone to contact you, as well as other information about you that is associated with that information, such as your account history. We collect Personal Information from you directly and from social networking platforms. In some cases, other people or organizations give us your Personal Information, such as third-party references.

We may also receive Personal Information about you from references that you provide us when you apply for opportunities with us, from other persons who have sent you gifts, included you in their membership or made donations in your name, or who have given us your information as their reference or emergency contact person.

Some of the information we collect is provided by you on our Site. In other cases, someone else shares it with us, such as someone who sends you a gift from our online store. This is called “User-Provided Information.” Some of the information we receive from your computer or device as you interact with our Site. This is called “Site Usage Information.”

## User-Provided Information

Depending on the type of application, we may collect Personal Information such as your name; Company name; age or date of birth; postal addresses; email addresses; telephone numbers; fax numbers; photograph; gender; credit card and other payment information; purchase, site browsing and transaction history; education and work history, allergy and medical conditions and other application information; and interests, hobbies and demographic information.

For example, we collect Personal Information when you buy tickets or make reservations for a visit to the museum, a program, a class or experience; purchase a membership, make a donation, create an account on our Site; sign up for our email updates; subscribe to one of our publications; make online purchases from our shop; answer a survey; enter a contest; complete an application to volunteer or for an internship or residency; apply for a job; apply to contribute to one of our publications, contribute to a blog or other social forum on the Site; or submit feedback or a comment, request or question to us using a “contact us,” “ask us” or similar feature on the Site.

You may purchase a gift or membership for another person in our online shop. We may ask you for the name and Personal Information of the other person, and that information will be protected pursuant to this privacy policy.

## Site Usage Information

Our servers automatically collect your IP address when you visit our Site, and we may associate that with your domain name or your Internet access provider, and your general location. We may also capture certain “clickstream data” pertaining to your Site usage. Clickstream data includes, for example, information about your computer or device, Web browser and operating system and their settings, the referring page that linked you to the Site, the pages, content or ads you see or click on during your visit and when and for how long you do so, items you download, the next website you visit when you leave the Site, and any search terms you have entered on the Site or a referral site.

Among other things, this information enables us to generate analytics reports on the usage of our Site. To opt out of your Site usage being included in our Google Analytics reports, you may follow <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

In addition, we use tracking technologies on our Site to improve user experience. For example:

  * Cookies are small data files stored on your computer or device at the request of a website. A cookie assigns a unique numerical identifier to your Web browser, and may enable us to recognize you as the same user who was at our Site in the past, and relate your use of the Site to other information about you, such as your Site usage information and Personal Information. Cookies may also be used to enhance your experience on the Site (for example, by storing your username so you can log in easily, keeping you logged into the Site after you have provided your password, and storing the contents of your shopping cart as you browse). Cookies also collect general usage and aggregated statistical information and detect and prevent fraud. Most browsers can be set to detect cookies and give you an opportunity to reject them, but refusing cookies may, in some cases, inhibit or preclude your use of the Site or its features.
  * A pixel tag (also known as a “clear GIF” or “web beacon”) is a tiny image – typically just one-pixel – that can be placed on a Web page or in our electronic communications to you in order to help us measure the effectiveness of our content by, for example, counting the number of individuals who visit us online or verifying whether you’ve opened one of our emails or seen one of our Web pages.
  * We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).  
You can opt out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

These tracking technologies may be used by us and by our service providers or partners. They enable us to assign a unique number or identifier to you and relate your Site Usage Information to other information about you, including your Personal Information. These technologies also enable us to recognize you when you access our Site using different Web browsers and different computers or devices.

## Social Networking

We maintain a presence on several third-party social networking platforms, and we also incorporate some third-party social networking features onto our Site. Examples are Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest, Reddit, Tumblr, Twitter and YouTube. Through these platforms and features, we may receive some Personal Information and some Site Usage Information about you, including your public posts about our museum, and this Privacy Policy applies to that information as well. In addition, third-party social networking platforms have their own privacy policies which explain how the third-parties that provide them will use and protect your information. In accordance with those policies (and your privacy settings within your social networking accounts) information about your activities on our Site (such when you share content from our Site on your social media profile) may be published to your social network.

## How is your information used?

We may use Personal Information to perform the following business functions:

  * enabling users to use our Site and its features;
  * processing and fulfilling your transactions and applications;
  * responding to your requests, questions, and concerns;
  * market research;
  * developing new features and offerings on the Site;
  * sending you communications, including information about offerings and events, of ours and of others, that we think might interest you, unless you ask us not to;
  * detecting and preventing fraud, and protecting our rights and property; and
  * other purposes disclosed when Personal Information is submitted to us.

## Collected Data Aggregation

We may match information collected from you through different means or at different times, including both Personal Information and Site Usage Information, and use such information along with information obtained from other sources (including third-parties) such as demographic information and updated contact information from data aggregators.

We may also use your information to assess the level of interest in, and use of, the Site, our emails and our other messaging campaigns both on an individual basis and in the aggregate.

## Do we share Personal Information and Site Usage Information with others?

Yes. We may share the information we collect on the Site with others for a variety of reasons, such as:

  * what you voluntarily post to a public area on the Site;
  * your name publicly on our website if you are an Ennion member, unless you have asked that your identity remain anonymous;
  * with our co-sponsor(s), in connection with an offering activity that is jointly offered by us and them;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or property, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a government, judicial or other legal request, or to comply with the law;
  * with our service providers so they can provide their services to us; and
  * in connection with an organizational change, such as if we were to merge our operations with another not-for-profit organization

We may share Personal Information and transaction history of our donors and members with a third-party data analytics firm that combines it with information received from other non-profit organizations and derives and reports to us, and to other non-profit organizations, recommendations regarding marketing initiatives, such as information about individuals’ likelihood to support non-profit causes by making donations and purchasing or upgrading memberships. If you do not want to have your information used in this way, you may send an email message to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f69297829786849f8097958fb6959b9991d8998491) containing your request to opt out of this use along with your name and email or postal address in your account with us, so that we can locate your account in our records and honor your request to opt out.

In addition, we may share non-personally identifiable Site Usage Information (including aggregate data) with others, for their own use, in a form that does not include your name or contact information.

## Third Party Ad Servers and Networks

Advertisements displayed to you on this Site and elsewhere may be customized to your interests and preferences based on your personally identifiable information and website usage Information collected through our Site and elsewhere online.

These companies may use Site Usage Information about your visits to this and other websites as well as other information about you in order to provide advertisements of interest to you. These advertisements may appear on this Site and on other websites. These companies may employ cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you. We encourage you to read these businesses’ privacy policies to learn about how they treat your information and to opt-out of uses that you do not consent to:

NAI’s consumer website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

Aboutads.info at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

Your Online Choices at <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/> (for European users)

Digital Alliance of Canada at <https://youradchoices.ca/> (for Canada users)

You have to opt-out using each of your Web browsing applications and devices separately. However, if you opt-out we may still suggest offerings to you on our Site based on your history at our Site.

## Do Not Track Disclosures

Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” (DNT) signals to the websites with which the user communicates. We currently do not change our tracking practices in response to DNT settings in your web browser. Our third-party web analytics companies and third-party ad networks collect information about your online activities over time and across our Site and other online properties. These third parties may not change their tracking practices in response to DNT settings in your web browser and we do not obligate these parties to honor DNT settings.

## Your Access Rights

You may review, update or modify certain of the Personal Information that is stored in your user account on the Site (if you have one) by logging in to the “My Account” or similar area of the Site or by contacting us using the “Contact Us” information below. We may ask you to verify your identity. Your right to delete your information is subject to our records retention policies and applicable law.

## Security

While we endeavor to protect the security and integrity of sensitive Personal Information collected via this Site, due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that any information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our system or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers.

If you create an account on our Site, you are responsible for maintaining the strict confidentiality of your account password, and you are responsible for any activity that occurs using your account credentials, whether or not you authorized such activity. Please notify us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#375e59515844525477545a585019584550) of any unauthorized use of your password or account or any other breach of security.

## “Linked-To” Websites

The Site may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for these other sites, and their posted privacy policies will govern the collection and use of your information on them. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each website visited after leaving the Site to learn about how your information is treated by others.

## Data Subject Rights

The Corning Museum of Glass is the “controller” of the Personal Information it collects on the Site. Under applicable law, you may have the right, where certain conditions are met:

  * to request access to the Personal Information we hold about you;
  * to have inaccurate information about you amended or updated (we endeavor to keep the Personal Information we store about you reasonably accurate and up-to-date by enabling you to correct it by request);
  * to object to processing of Personal Information about you;
  * to withdraw consent at any time (where relevant);
  * to have Personal Information about you erased or to restrict processing in certain limited situations;
  * to data portability and to request the transmission of Personal Information about you to another organization;
  * to object to automated decision making that materially impacts you, direct marketing, and processing for research or statistical purposes; and
  * to lodge complaints with applicable regulators and data supervisory authorities particularly in the jurisdiction where you live.

You may use the contact information below to get more information and/or to make a formal request.

## Legal Basis for Processing Personal Information

We use your Personal Information where it is necessary for us to enter into or perform under an agreement with you (if we have one with you). We also use it for our legitimate interests to provide our Site and offerings, and to communicate with you, so long as our doing so does not encroach upon your interests and fundamental rights weighed against our legitimate interests. For example, in order for us to operate our website and provide you with our offerings, it is necessary for us to collect certain data about you. In addition, we use Personal Information to send communications to you and to personalize our offerings to you, with your consent and otherwise to the extent allowed by applicable law.

## Disclosure & Retention of Data Subjects’ Personal Information

A Data Subject is any individual person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, via an identifier such as a name, an ID number, etc. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that where Personal Information of Data Subjects is shared with third parties, it is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy and applicable laws.

We will endeavor not to keep Personal Information in a form that allows you to be identified for any longer than is reasonably necessary for achieving the permitted purposes. At the end of the applicable retention period, we may destroy, erase from our systems, or anonymize Personal Information as part of such efforts. To determine the appropriate retention period for Personal Information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the Personal Information, the purposes for which we process the Personal Information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

## Storage & Transfer of Data Subjects’ Personal Information

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards designed to protect Personal Information, prevent unlawful or unauthorized processing of Personal Information, and prevent unauthorized disclosure of, or accidental loss of, or damage to, such information.

If you are located outside of the United States, you should know that the information you provide to us is being transmitted to us and processed in the United States and will be protected subject to this privacy policy and United States laws, which may not be as protective as the laws in your country.

Personal information will be processed by staff who work for us and operate outside the European Economic Area. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the provision of administration and support services. All such staff are subject to appropriate confidentiality and security obligations. We restrict access to non-public Personal Information to those of our employees and agents who need to know the information to enable us to provide services.

We will only transfer Personal Information to third party service providers if they agree to comply with the physical, electronic and procedural safeguards described above, or if they put in place adequate measures themselves.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Policy from time to time. When we do, we will let you know by posting the changed Policy on this page with a new “Effective Date.” If we significantly expand our use or sharing of your Personal Information, we may also tell you about these changes by additional means, such as by sending an email to the email address we have on file for you. In some cases, we may request your consent to the changes.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy practices, you may contact us at:

Corning Museum of Glass  
One Museum Way  
Corning, New York 14830  
U.S.A.

We also can be reached by phone at 1-800-732-6845 and by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#93fef2fafffafdf4fffae0e7e0d3f0fefcf4bdfce1f4)

Effective Date: September 23, 2019
